A Guide to the Governor Robert F. McDonnell, Executive Office-Counselor's Office, Records, 2002-2003; 2006-2013 (bulk 2010-2013)
Library of Virginia
Library of Virginia
Governor Robert F. McDonnell, Executive Office-Counselor's Office, Records 2002-2003; 2006-2013 (bulk 2010-2013)
The Library of Virginia
51143
8.5 cu. ft. (15 boxes)
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
Collection is open to research.
Acquisition Information
Office of the Governor, Patrick Henry Building, 1111 E. Broad Street, Richmond, Virginia, 23219, accession 51143 transferred on 9 January 2014 and 23 January 2014.
Biographical Information
The Executive Office is a division of the Office of the Governor in the Executive Branch of Virginia state government. Members of the Executive Office include the Governor, Chief of Staff, Counselor to the Governor and their assistants. On 12 January 2010, Governor-elect Robert F. McDonnell appointed J. Jasen Eige as counselor and senior advisor to the governor. Eige's duties included providing legal counsel and advice to the Governor and his Administration, and assisting with policy and legislative matters. Governor McDonnell promoted Eige to counselor and senior policy advisor in June 2011. In this cabinet-level position, Eige oversaw the Governor's Policy Office, including the direction of the administration's policy and legislative efforts.
Jasen Eige first worked with Governor-elect Bob McDonnell in 1999 as an intern in his legislative office during law school. After law school, Eige clerked for the Honorable Glen M. Williams, Senior United States District Judge for the Western District of Virginia. He then joined the Abingdon law firm of Penn, Stuart and Eskridge as an associate. In 2003 he and his wife, Christy, moved from Bristol, Virginia to Richmond to work in Attorney General Jerry Kilgore's Administration as an Assistant Attorney General in the Trial Section of the Civil Litigation Section. In 2006 he was promoted to Senior Assistant Attorney General in the Finance Law and Government Services Section, where he later served as Acting Section Chief for the Government Services portion of the Section. In this capacity, Eige directly managed attorneys and support staff for this Section and represented several state agencies including the Virginia State Board of Elections, Virginia Department of Agriculture, the Virginia Port Authority, the Virginia College Savings Fund, the Virginia Retirement System, the Virginia Department of Economic Development, and the Virginia Small Business Financing Authority.
In 2007, Eige began serving as Chief of Staff and Counsel to then-Attorney General Robert F. McDonnell. Among other duties, he oversaw the Administrative Division of the Office of the Attorney General including the Finance, Technology and Human Resource Departments. During this period, Eige assisted with achieving zero audit points for the last two years of the McDonnell Administration, and played a critical role in cutting the office budget by more than 19 percent, without layoffs. Eige also took over Deputy Attorney General responsibilities for the Financial Law and Government Services Division, overseeing attorneys and support staff in that Division. In 2009, Eige joined Governor-elect McDonnell's gubernatorial campaign as Chief Counsel. He currently serves as Counsel to the Governor-elect's Transition Office.
Eige earned his Juris Doctor and Masters in Public Policy degrees at Regent University, after attending King College in Bristol, Tennessee, where he received a Bachelors of Arts in political science and history. [Biography taken from Governor-elect McDonnell press release issued 12 January 2010.]
The Counselor was assisted in these responsibilities by a Deputy Counselor. The following individuals held this positions during Governor McDonnell's administration (2010-2014): Stephanie Hamlett (March-July 2010), J. Randall Minchew (August 2010-2011), and Jeff Palmore (July 2011-September 2013).
Scope and Content
The Governor Robert F. McDonnell, Executive Office-Counselor's Office, Records are housed in 15 boxes. The collection is arranged into four (4) series. Series have been designated for: I. General Files of the Counselor to the Governor; II. Clemency Files; III. Judges; and IV. Attorney General Settlements. These records include agreements, reports, correspondence, e-mail, memorandums, legal briefs, legal files, budget documents, agendas, handouts, and meeting notes. This collection documents the actions of Governor McDonnell's Counselor's Office. Parts of series I and all of series II, III and IV are closed for 75 years per Code of Virginia, 2.2-3705.1 (attorney-client privilege).
Arrangement
This collection is arranged into the following series:
I. General Files of the Counselor to the Governor, 2008-2013 (bulk 2010-2013)
II. Clemency Files, 2002-2003; 2006-2012 (bulk 2010-2012)
III. Judges, 2011-2012
IV. Attorney General Settlements, 2010-2011
Related Material
OFFICE OF THE GOVERNOR-ROBERT F. MCDONNELL
The Governor Robert F. McDonnell Administration Web Archive Collection, 2010-2014
The Correspondence and Supporting Documentation of the Executive Office of Governor Robert F. McDonnell, 2010-2013 (bulk 2010-2011) Collection
The Records of Governor Robert F. McDonnell's Governor Robert F. McDonnell, Executive Office-Deputy Chief of Staff Matt Conrad, Records, 2011-2013 Collection
The Records of the Executive Mansion of Governor Robert F. McDonnell, 2010-2014 Collection
CABINET OF GOVERNOR ROBERT F. MCDONNELL
The Records of the Office of the Secretary of Administration, 2010-2013 Collection
The Records of the Office of the Secretary of Agriculture and Forestry, 2005-2013 (bulk 2010-2013) Collection
The Records of the Office of the Secretary of Commerce and Trade, 1998-2014 (bulk 2010-2013) Collection
The Records of the Office of the Secretary of Education, 2006-2014 (bulk 2009-2013) Collection
The Records of the Office of the Secretary of Finance, 2007-2013 Collection
The Records of the Office of the Secretary of Health and Human Resources, 2010-2013 Collection
The Records of the Office of the Secretary of Natural Resources, 2002-2014 (bulk 2009-2013) Collection
The Records of the Office of the Secretary of Public Safety and Homeland Security, 2006-2013 (bulk 2010-2013) Collection
The Records of the Office of the Secretary of Public Safety, 2010-2013 (bulk 2012-2013) Collection
The Records of the Secretary of Transportation, 2009-2013 Collection
The Records of the Secretary of Veterans Affairs and Homeland Security, 2005-2012 (bulk 2010-2011) Collection
SECRETARY OF THE COMMONWEALTH FOR GOVERNOR ROBERT F. MCDONNELL
The Records of the Secretary of the Commonwealth, 2010-2014 Collection
The Constituent Correspondence of Governor Robert F. McDonnell, 2009-2013 (bulk 2010-2013) Collection
The Constituent Correspondence of Governor Robert F. McDonnell, Mass Mailings, 2009-2013 (bulk 2010-2013) Collection
The Records of the Secretary of the Commonwealth, Governor's Fellows Program, 2010-2011 Collection
The Records of the Secretary of the Commonwealth, Oaths, 1998-2013 Collection
The Records of the Secretary of the Commonwealth, Working Files and Tracking Documents, 2010-2014 (bulk 2011-2013) Collection
Contents List
- I. General Files of the Counselor to the Governor, 2008-2013 (bulk 2010-2013)., Extent: 5.0 cubic feet (5 boxes). (Box 1-5)
  The General Files of the Counselor to the Governor series is housed in five boxes and is arranged alphabetically by subject. This series contains the records of J. Jasen Eige, Counselor and Senior Advisor to the Governor (2010-2014). Beginning in June 2011, Eige also lead the Policy Office and his records reflect both of these roles. Also included are a small number of files created by Deputy Counselor Stephanie Hamlett (March-July 2010), Jeff Palmore (July 2011-September 2013) and Mark Rubin, former counselor to Governor Tim Kaine (2009-2010). Confidential, privacy-protected and attorney-client privileged records are closed for 75 years per Code of Virginia, 2.2-3705.1, 2.2-3800 and 42.1-78. Restricted records in this collection have been sealed but not removed from the collection.
  Notable subjects include: the 2012 settlement agreement between the Commonwealth and United State Department of Justice to address the failure of the Commonwealth to provide services to individuals with intellectual disabilities in the most integrated setting appropriate to their needs as required by the Americans Disabilities Act and US Supreme Court's Olmstead Decision; the development of the McDonnell administration pardon and restoration of rights procedures; Governor's Commission on Government Reform and Restructuring; legal challenges to the federal Patient Protection and Affordable Care Act of 2010; review of previous issued executive orders; plans and litigation related redistricting in Virginia after the 2010 census; amendments to the Comprehensive Infrastructure Agreement between the Virginia Information Technology Agency (VITA) and Northrup Grumman (NG); Republican Party of Virginia challenges to the petitions of the Libertarian Party and Constitution Party to be on the ballot for the 2012 presidential election; and settlement agreements between the Commonwealth and individuals injured and the estates of those killed at Virginia Tech on 16 April 2007.
  - 2011 Commissions and Workgroups (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - 2011 Session, 2011 (1 of 2) (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - 2011 Session, 2011 (2 of 2) (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - 10th Amendment/Federalism, 2010 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Alternative Onsite Sewage Systems Regulations, 2011 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Amazon Tax Issue, 2012 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - American Recovery and Reinvestment Act (ARRA)-Federal Grants, 2010 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Arizona's Immigration Law, 2010 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Aspen Institute - Healthcare Roundtable, 2011 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Attorney General Memos, 2011 (RESTRICTED) (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Attorney General Opinion - Charitable Funding (O'Bannon), 2011 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Attorney General Opinions, 2010-2011; 2013 (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Behavioral Health - United States Dept. of Justice Settlements, 2011 (1 of 5) (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - Behavioral Health - United States Dept. of Justice Settlements, 2011 (2 of 5) (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - Behavioral Health - United States Dept. of Justice Settlements, 2010 (3 of 5) (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - Behavioral Health - United States Dept. of Justice Settlements, 2010 (4 of 5) (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - Behavioral Health - United States Dept. of Justice Settlements, 2010-2011 (5 of 5) (Box 1, Folder 17)
  - Bristol Tax Matter, 2013 (Box 1, Folder 18)
  - Budget Amendments, 2010 (Box 1, Folder 19)
  - Cabinet Meeting Agenda, 7 March 2011 (Box 1, Folder 20)
  - CGI Management Agreement, 2010-2012 (Box 1, Folder 21)
  - Charter Schools/College Labs, Constitutional Issues, undated (Box 1, Folder 22)
  - Chesapeake Bay Total Maximum Daily Load (TMDL): Legal Options, 2010-2011 (RESTRICTED) (Box 1, Folder 23)
  - Chinese Drywall, 2010 (Box 1, Folder 24)
  - Clemency
    - State Law Summary for Restoration of Rights, 2013 (Box 1, Folder 25)
    - Pardon Procedures, 2011 (Box 1, Folder 26)
    - Pardon and Restoration of Rights Procedures, 2010-2011 (Box 1, Folder 27)
    - Pardon and Restoration of Rights Research, 2010-2011 (1 of 2) (Box 1, Folder 28)
    - Pardon and Restoration of Rights Research, 2010-2011 (2 of 2) (Box 1, Folder 29)
  - Cobbs Creek Reservoir Project (Henrico County), 2012-2013 (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - Constitutional Convention-Repeal Amendment, 2010 (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - Delegation of Authority (EO 4), 2010 (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - Eastern State Hospital-Decertification, 2010 (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - Election Day 2012, 2012 (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - Emergency Management Volunteer Groups, undated (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - Eminent Domain, 2012 (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - EPA - Chesapeake Bay, 2010 (Box 2, Folder 8)
  - EPA - Surface Mining Litigation, 2010 (Box 2, Folder 9)
  - Executive Directive 1 (2010) - Employment Discrimination (Box 2, Folder 10)
  - Executive Order - Children's Services Transformation, 2010 (Box 2, Folder 11)
  - Executive Orders, 2010; 2012 (Box 2, Folder 12)
  - Executive Orders-Summer 2010 (Box 2, Folder 13)
  - Executive Reorganization Plans, undated (Box 2, Folder 14)
  - Fairfax Litigation, 2010 (Box 2, Folder 15)
  - Fees Issue-HB 3202 (2007), 2010 (Box 2, Folder 16)
  - Firearms in State Parks and State Forests, 2010 (Box 2, Folder 17)
  - Freedom of Information Act (FOIA) Requests (Historic), 2012-2013 (Box 2, Folder 18)
  - Goochland County Treasurer Matter, 2011 (Box 2, Folder 19)
  - Governor's Advisory Council on Revenue Estimates (GACRE), 23 November 2009 Meeting (Box 2, Folder 20)
  - Boards and Commissions Elimination and Consolidation, 2011 (1 of 4) (Box 2, Folder 21)
  - Boards and Commissions Elimination and Consolidation, 2011 (2 of 4) (Box 2, Folder 22)
  - Boards and Commissions Elimination and Consolidation, 2011 (3 of 4) (Box 2, Folder 23)
  - Boards and Commissions Elimination and Consolidation, 2011 (4 of 4) (Box 2, Folder 24)
  - Gubernatorial Powers Under Federal Law by National Governors Association, undated (Box 2, Folder 25)
  - Gun Background Checks, 2011 (Box 2, Folder 26)
  - Gunston Hall, 2011 (Box 2, Folder 27)
  - HB 1160: barring Virginia Participation with Military Detentions of Virginians under National Defense Authorization Act of 2012, 2012 (Box 2, Folder 28)
  - Stephanie Hamlett's Research, 2010 (1 of 2) (Box 2, Folder 29)
  - Stephanie Hamlett's Research, 2010 (2 of 2) (Box 2, Folder 30)
  - Healthcare Lawsuit-Sign-on Letter, 2011 (Box 2, Folder 31)
  - Health Care Reform-General Information, 2010 (Box 2, Folder 32)
  - Health Care Reform Taskforce, 2010 (Box 2, Folder 33)
  - Hernandez v. Commonwealth - Deferred Disposition, 2011 (Box 2, Folder 34)
  - Hiring Freeze Policy, 2010 (Box 2, Folder 35)
  - James River Correctional Center Environmental Issues, 2010 (Box 2, Folder 36)
  - Jasen Eige Meetings with OAG, May 2010 (Box 2, Folder 37)
  - JIRC Appointments, 2010 (Box 2, Folder 38)
  - Judges, 2013 (Box 2, Folder 39)
  - Judicial District Boundaries, 2011 (Box 2, Folder 40)
  - Legal Correspondence, 2010 (Box 2, Folder 41)
  - Legal Correspondence, 2011 (Box 2, Folder 42)
  - Legal Correspondence, 2012 and undated (Box 2, Folder 43)
  - Legislative Process/Research, 2010 (Box 2, Folder 44)
  - Line of Duty Act, 2011-2012 (Box 2, Folder 45)
  - Litigation-Health Care Reform (Virginia v. Sebelius), 2010 (Box 2, Folder 46)
  - Local Mandates, 2011-2012 (Box 2, Folder 47)
  - Local Mandates, 2010 (Box 2, Folder 48)
  - Longitudinal Data Systems, 2009 (Box 2, Folder 49)
  - Mandatory Minimum-Juveniles, 2012 (RESTRICTED) (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - Maryland Fishing License Matter, 2010 (Box 3, Folder 2)
  - Miller v. Alabama, 2012 (Box 3, Folder 3)
  - Miscellaneous Correspondence, 2012 (Box 3, Folder 4)
  - Miscellaneous Correspondence to Mark Rubin, Counselor to Governor Tim Kaine, 2009-2010 (Box 3, Folder 5)
  - Miscellaneous Legal Matters, 2010-2013 (Box 3, Folder 6)
  - Miscellaneous Letters, Jeff Palmore, 2011-2012 (Box 3, Folder 7)
  - Miscellaneous Litigation, 2013 (Box 3, Folder 8)
  - NAACP, undated (Box 3, Folder 9)
  - National Governors Association (NGA) Virginia Chamber Memorandum of Understanding, 2011 (Box 3, Folder 10)
  - Norfolk Four, 2010 (Box 3, Folder 11)
  - Office of the Inspector General Semi-Annual Report, 2010 (Box 3, Folder 12)
  - Office of State Inspector General, Creation, 2011 (Box 3, Folder 13)
  - Ohio River Valley Water Sanitation Commission (ORSANCO), 2010 (Box 3, Folder 14)
  - Outdoor Advertising Matter (Lamar, et al), 2010 (Box 3, Folder 15)
  - Outside Counsel, Correspondence and Invoices, 2010 (Box 3, Folder 16)
  - Outside Counsel, Correspondence and Invoices, 2011 (Box 3, Folder 17)
  - Outside Counsel, Correspondence and Invoices, 2011-2013 (Box 3, Folder 18)
  - Outside Counsel, undated (Box 3, Folder 19)
  - Parole Board - Class Action, 2009 (Box 3, Folder 20)
  - Pelham "Confederate Memorial" Chapel Lease, 2010 (Box 3, Folder 21)
  - Pending Litigation, 2010 (Box 3, Folder 22)
  - Petroleum Storage Fund, 2009 (Box 3, Folder 23)
  - Previous Executive Orders, 2010 (1 of 3) (Box 3, Folder 24)
  - Previous Executive Orders, 2010 (2 of 3) (Box 3, Folder 25)
  - Previous Executive Orders, 2010 (3 of 3) (Box 3, Folder 26)
  - Proclamations Process, undated (Box 3, Folder 27)
  - Qualified School Construction Bond (QSCB)-2010 Allocation, 2010-2011 (Box 3, Folder 28)
  - Real Estate Liens in Virginia Beach-BRAC, 2010 (Box 3, Folder 29)
  - Recognized Virginia Tribes, 2010 (Box 3, Folder 30)
  - Recovermetrics, 2002; 2013 (Box 3, Folder 31)
  - Recovery Zone Bond Allocation Sports Quest, 2010 (Box 3, Folder 32)
  - Redistricting, 2010-2011 (folder 1 of 4) (Box 3, Folder 33)
  - Redistricting (Plans), 2010-2011 (folder 2 of 4) (Box 3, Folder 34)
  - Redistricting, 2011 (folder 3 of 4) (Box 3, Folder 35)
  - Redistricting, 2010-2011 (folder 4 of 4) (Box 3, Folder 36)
  - Redistricting Commission, 2010-2011 (Jeff Palmore files) (Box 4, Folder 1)
  - Redistricting, Legal Issues, 2010-2011 (1 of 3) (Box 4, Folder 2)
  - Redistricting, Legal Issues, 2010-2011 (2 of 3) (Box 4, Folder 3)
  - Redistricting, Legal Issues, 2010-2011 (3 of 3) (Box 4, Folder 4)
  - Redistricting Litigation, 2011 (Box 4, Folder 5)
  - Regulatory Process and Procedures, 2010 (Box 4, Folder 6)
  - Regulatory Reform, 2013 (Box 4, Folder 7)
  - Rendition Procedures, undated (Box 4, Folder 8)
  - Requests for Temporary Custody of Deanna M. Lansdown and Moses Davis, 2010 (Box 4, Folder 9)
  - Restoration of Rights Project, 2013 (Box 4, Folder 10)
  - Rotunda v. Zengerle, et al, 2009-2010 (Box 4, Folder 11)
  - RSW Regional Jail, 2011-2012 (Box 4, Folder 12)
  - SB 192/HB 1291, 2010 (RESTRICTED) (Box 4, Folder 13)
  - Seguin v. Circuit court of Fairfax County, 2010 (Box 4, Folder 14)
  - Sex Offender Registration and Notification Act (SORNA), 2011 (Box 4, Folder 15)
  - Sexually Violent Predator Program, 2011-2012 (Box 4, Folder 16)
  - Single Sales Factor Apportionment for Retailers, 2011 (Box 4, Folder 17)
  - Southern Growth Policies Board, 2008-2010 (Box 4, Folder 18)
  - Special Counsel Appointed for Pierce Homer, 2010 (Box 4, Folder 19)
  - Special Elections, 2010 (Box 4, Folder 20)
  - Special Elections, 2011 (Box 4, Folder 21)
  - Special Elections-January 2011, 2010-2011 (Box 4, Folder 22)
  - State Bar Dues, 2011 (Box 4, Folder 23)
  - State Fraud, Waste, and Abuse Hotline, 2012 (Box 4, Folder 24)
  - State Police Chaplain Prayer, 2010 (folder 1 of 2) (Box 4, Folder 25)
  - State Police Chaplain Prayer, 2010 (folder 2 of 2) (Box 4, Folder 26)
  - Tort Reform, 2011 (Box 4, Folder 27)
  - Two-Term Governor, 2010 (Box 4, Folder 28)
  - University of Virginia/Civil Investigative Demand, 2010 (Box 4, Folder 29)
  - Virginia Commonwealth University (VCU) Performance Management Group, 2010 (Box 4, Folder 30)
  - Virginia Dept. of Business Assistance, 2011 (Box 4, Folder 31)
  - Virginia Dept. of Emergency Management (VDEM), Decision Brief for costs of Virginia Tech shootings, 2010 (Box 4, Folder 32)
  - Virginia Dept. of Historic Resources, Justin French Investigation, 2010 (Box 4, Folder 33)
  - Virginia Dept. of Human Resource Management Regulations-Expanding State Employee Health Insurance Benefits, 2010 (RESTRICTED) (Box 4, Folder 34)
  - Virginia Dept. of Juvenile Justice, Nondiscrimination Regulations, 2011 (Box 4, Folder 35)
  - Virginia Dept. of Medical Assistance (DMAS) Data Match Regulation, 2010 (Box 4, Folder 36)
  - Virginia Information Technology Agency (VITA)-Northrup Grumman (NG) Amendments to the Comprehensive Infrastructure Agreement, 2010 (1 of 3) (Box 4, Folder 37)
  - Virginia Information Technology Agency (VITA)-Northrup Grumman (NG) Amendments to the Comprehensive Infrastructure Agreement, 2010 (2 of 3) (Box 4, Folder 38)
  - Virginia Information Technology Agency (VITA)-Northrup Grumman (NG) Amendments to the Comprehensive Infrastructure Agreement, 2010 (3 of 3) (Box 4, Folder 39)
  - Virginia Information Technology Agency (VITA)-Northrup Grumman (NG) Contract Renegotiation, 2010 (1 of 2) (Box 4, Folder 40)
  - Virginia Information Technology Agency (VITA)-Northrup Grumman (NG) Contract Renegotiation, 2010 (2 of 2) (Box 5, Folder 1)
  - Virginia Information Technology Agency (VITA)-Northrup Grumman (NG), Memorandum of Agreement Regarding Operational Audit and August 2010 Outage, 2011 (Box 5, Folder 2)
  - Virginia Information Technology (VITA)/Northrup Grumman (NG) Outage, 2010 (Box 5, Folder 3)
  - Virginia Liaison Office, 2010 (Box 5, Folder 4)
  - Virginia Lottery ADA Case (Winborne v. Lottery), 2010 (Box 5, Folder 5)
  - Virginia Port Authority, Lease Agreement with APM Terminals, 2009 (Box 5, Folder 6)
  - Virginia Port Authority, Legal Issues, 2012 (Box 5, Folder 7)
  - Virginia State Board of Elections
    - Nomination Petitions of Edward Clark, Libertarian Party, 2012 (1 of 2) (Box 5, Folder 8)
    - Nomination Petitions of Edward Clark, Libertarian Party, 2012 (2 of 2) (Box 5, Folder 9)
    - Nomination Petitions of Virgil Hamlin Goode, Constitution Party, 2012 (1 of 6) (Box 5, Folder 10)
    - Nomination Petitions of Virgil Hamlin Goode, Constitution Party, 2012 (2 of 6) (Box 5, Folder 11)
    - Nomination Petitions of Virgil Hamlin Goode, Constitution Party, 2012 (3 of 6) (Box 5, Folder 12)
    - Nomination Petitions of Virgil Hamlin Goode, Constitution Party, 2012 (4 of 6) (Box 5, Folder 13)
    - Nomination Petitions of Virgil Hamlin Goode, Constitution Party, 2012 (5 of 6) (Box 5, Folder 14)
    - Nomination Petitions of Virgil Hamlin Goode, Constitution Party, 2012 (6 of 6) (Box 5, Folder 15)
  - Virginia Tech - Indemnification Agreement between Virginia Tech and President Charles Steger, 2013 (RESTRICTED) (Box 5, Folder 16)
  - Virginia Tech - Lawsuit (Peterson/Pryde v. Thyden, et al), 2010-2012 (Box 5, Folder 17)
  - Virginia Tech Report, 2010 (Box 5, Folder 18)
  - Virginia Tech - Settlement, 2010 (Box 5, Folder 19)
  - Virginia Tech - Settlement Agreements (Deceased), A-H, 2008 (Box 5, Folder 20)
  - Virginia Tech - Settlement Agreements (Deceased), L-O, 2008 (Box 5, Folder 21)
  - Virginia Tech - Settlement Agreements (Deceased), P-W, 2008 (Box 5, Folder 22)
  - Virginia Tech - Settlement Agreements (Injured), C-K, 2008 (Box 5, Folder 23)
  - Virginia Tech - Settlement Agreements (Injured), M-W, 2008 (Box 5, Folder 24)
  - Voter ID, 2012 (Box 5, Folder 25)
  - Williamsburg Tourism Visitor Center, 2010 (Box 5, Folder 26)
- II. Clemency Files, 2002-2003; 2006-2012 (bulk 2010-2012)., Extent: 3.5 cubic feet (10 boxes). (Box 6-15)
  The Clemency Files series is housed in 10 boxes. This series contains clemency petitions from prisoners submitted to the Governor. The clemency petitions usually include: petition from prisoner, constituent letters (for and against clemency), court documents and opinions, summary of the case provided by the Office of the Attorney General, and a memorandum to Governor McDonnell from Counselor to the Governor Jasen Eige, providing background information on the case, analysis of petition and conclusion/recommendation to Governor. Files are arranged alphabetically. This series also includes a few medical pardon applications and international prisoner requests.This series contains confidential, privacy-protected and attorney-client privileged records and is closed for 75 years per Code of Virginia, 2.2-3705.1, 2.2-3800 and 42.1-78.
  Clemency records were submitted on behalf of: Mario Bustillo, Thomas Haynesworth, Jerry Jackson (executed 18 August 2011), Teresa Lewis (executed 23 September 2010), Johnathan Montgomery, Paul Powell (executed 18 March 2010), Davey Reedy, Jens Soering and Darick Walker (executed May 20, 2010).
  - Mario Bustillo, 2002 (1 of 11) (Box 6, Folder 1)